Manuel Galicia

5 years of experience, 4 years in Tech Recruitment

+1 (438) 836-2057 Manuel.ed.roga@gmail.com

I am passionate about 3 things: Recruiting, Coding and Star Wars!

Experienced Technical Recruiter, skillful in every step of a hiring process. I specialize in every step from writing a job description, negotiating terms with the company, all the way to making the candidates feel at home in their new company. If you need Developers of any stack, Data Engineers, DevOps Engineers, Cloud Engineers, DBAs and much more, I am the Recruiter you need!

Experience

09/2021 to Present

Technical Recruiter (Remote)

VanHack Vancouver, BC

- Sales/Recruitment environment
- Hire technical personnel from various backgrounds depending on the company's needs. (Devs, SREs, DE etc.)
- Directly responsible on producing the company \$450k of revenue on average per year.
- Negotiate terms and expectations with companies based on their requirements.
- Interviewed/Screened +700 different candidates
- Positioned +40 candidates in top tech companies all across Canada.
- In charge of the Full-cycle recruitment.
- Sourcing and Headhunting were part of my day-to-day.

01/2019 to 09/2021

Senior Tech Recruiter (Remote) Survey, Boston, MA

- High volume recruitment for technical and non-technical positions.
- Hired +400 workers in the span of 1.5 years.
- Led Pilot initiatives to develop new strategies for the recruitment market.

07/2017 to 12/2019

Team Lead Account Manager (Remote) Market Resource Partners, Philadelphia, PA

- Helped company hire internally as well as handle account management
- Hired +25 members in the tech department.

Highlights

- Familiar with various ATS (Greenday, JazzHR, BambooHR and many more)
- Results-oriented
- Jr Python Dev
- Effective work ethic
- Organizational capacity
- Commitment
- Ability to motivate staff and maintain good relations
- Resistance to stress
- Good manners
- Open to all the feedback in the world!

Education

Bachelor of International Business: UAM American University

Hobbies

- Coding: Jr. Python Dev that constantly learns.
- Gaming: Love gaming in every aspect!
- Star Wars